{
    "1": {
      "question": "Whose death sparked World War I?:\n(a) Kaiser Wilhelm\n(b) Archbishop Ussher\n(c) Queen Victoria\n(d) Archduke Franz Ferdinand\n",
      "answer": "d",
      "more_info": "On June 28, 1914, Archduke Franz (Francis) Ferdinand of Austria-Hungary was assassinated. His murder led to World War I.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "2": {
      "question": "2) Which of these nations was neutral in World War I?:\n(a) Germany\n(b) Norway\n(c) Italy\n(d) England\n",
      "answer": "b",
      "more_info": "Norway was neutral, meaning that it did not take sides, during World War I (1914–18). The country did not want to enter World War II (1939–45) either, but Nazi Germany invaded it in 1940.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "3": {
      "question": "3) Which of these ships was sunk by a German submarine?:\n(a) Arizona\n(b) Lusitania\n(c) Titanic\n(d) Andrea Doria\n",
      "answer": "b",
      "more_info": "The British passenger ship Lusitania was sunk by a German submarine off the coast of Ireland in 1915, causing great loss of life.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "4": {
      "question": "Which weapon was first used at the Battle of the Somme in World War I?:\n(a) Submarine\n(b) Tank\n(c) Jet fighter\n(d) Chariot\n",
      "answer": "b",
      "more_info": "The tank was introduced, at first by the British armed forces, at the Battle of the Somme during World War I.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "5": {
      "question": " World War I ended in:\n(a) 1925\n(b) 1920\n(c) 1918\n(d) 1915\n",
      "answer": "c",
      "more_info": "World War I officially ended at 11 AM on November 11 (11/11), 1918.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "6": {
      "question": " Which of these people was a spy in World War I?:\n(a) Mata Hari\n(b) James Bond\n(c) Benedict Arnold\n(d) Serge Plekhanov\n",
      "answer": "a",
      "more_info": "Mata Hari was a spy for Germany during World War I. She was executed in 1917.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "7": {
      "question": "Which Indian president was involved in the struggle for Irish independence?:\n(a) V.V. Giri\n(b) Neelam Sanjiva Reddy\n(c) Gulzarilal Nanda\n(d) S. Radhakrishnan\n",
      "answer": "a",
      "more_info": "V.V. Giri, India’s president from 1969 to 1974, studied in Dublin, Ireland, where he became involved in the movement to free Ireland from British rule.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "8": {
      "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to appear on television?:\n(a) Richard Nixon\n(b) Ronald Reagan\n(c) Abraham Lincoln\n(d) Franklin Delano Roosevelt\n",
      "answer": "d",
      "more_info": "Appearing at the 1939 World’s Fair in New York City, Franklin D. Roosevelt became the first U.S. president to be televised.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "9": {
      "question": "Who was Karl Marx’s associate and fellow political theoretician?:\n(a) Friedrich Nietzsche\n(b) Friedrich II\n(c) Friedrich Engels\n(d) Friedrich Reich\n",
      "asnswer": "c",
      "more_info": "In 1844, Karl Marx met a young socialist named Friedrich Engels, with whom he developed many of his ideas.",
      "user_response": "None"
    },
    "10": {
      "question": "How many republics made up the former Soviet Union?:\n(a) 15\n(b) 12\n(c) 20\n(d) 10\n",
      "answer": "a",
      "more_info": "The Soviet Union, at its end, was made up of 15 republics. The largest and most powerful was the Russian Soviet Federated Socialist Republic, now Russia.",
      "user_response": "None"
    }
  
  }